喂  伴郎
Hey, best man.
《摩登家庭》前情提要
是啊  我也觉得你应该叫我"伴人"
Yeah, I think I might go with "Best person."
又是老妈的事吗  我说过了  我没事
Is this about mom again? I told you, I'm fine.
我只是有点同情你
I was just a little sad for you.
老妈爽约了
Mom's a no-show,
你和老爸又几乎不说话
and you and dad are hardly even speaking.
我要抛弃你
I'm leaving you!
但我要先抛弃你
Not if I leave you first!
你干了什么
What did you do?!
注意  各位请注意
Attention! Attention, please!
大火已经漫过高速了
The fire has jumped the freeway.
等等  等等等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
如果你们要疏散整个区域
If you're evacuating the whole area,
能不能最后疏散我们
can't you just do us last?
恐怕你们还没意识到
I don't think you realize
你们离实际火源有多近
how close you are to actual flames.
你好  我是胡娇・萨茨曼
Hello. Pepper Saltzman.
你们的忠实粉丝
Big supporter of yours.
我收藏了你们所有的年历
Have all your calendars.
我们已经等了10年
We've waited 10 years.
能给我们一个小时吗
Can we please have an hour?
只能给你们30分钟
I can give you 30 minutes.
那样就够了
We can make that work!
婚礼稍微简化  继续进行
The wedding will go on just in a slightly pared-down version.
克莱尔  你到前面去
Claire, you're up front.
花童  撒花去
Flower girl, strewing.
新郎们  跟我来
Grooms, come with me.
他们看起来好帅啊
"Ooh! Ahh! They look so handsome!"
四重唱  四重唱  四重唱
Quartet, quartet, quartet!
萨尔该你了  五行打油诗就别念了
And cue Sal. Start after your limerick.
天呐  不
Oh, God, no!
我们都得牺牲一些  亲爱的
Ugh! We're all making sacrifices, dear.
我那还有一车的帝王蝶
I have a Prius full of monarch butterflies
看来是要跟我回家了
who are apparently coming home with me.
不是吧
Aah! No!
她羊水破了
Her water broke!
不  没有破  我才刚刚怀孕
No! No, it did not! I am barely pregnant!
感谢各位莅临这个大喜的日子
Thank you all for being here on this joyous occasion.
曾有一个基佬名叫塔克
There once was a homo named Tucker --
萨尔  快停下  不行  你要分娩了
Sal, stop. No, you're going into labor!
行行好  快停下吧
Also, just stop!
但我们才在一起四个月啊
But we've only been together four months.
我太爱你了
I just love you so much,
迫不及待想要生出你的孩子
I can't wait to have your baby.
天呐  孩子把一切都毁了
God! Kids ruin everything!
是啊  没错
Yeah, they sure do.
我带你去医院  生下我们的奇迹宝宝吧
Let's get you to the hospital and have our miracle baby.
好
Okay.
只是要告知你一下
Just so you know,
有时这么早产的孩子
sometimes when babies come this early...
生出来是黑皮肤的
...they're black.
彻底灾难了
Okay, this is a disaster!
没人为我们证婚了
We have no one to marry us!
亲爱的人们  这确实是个问题
Dearly beloved, that is a problem.
是啊
Yep.
感谢35美元和互联网
Thanks to $35 and the internet,
您现在看到的是
you are looking at
好牧师菲利普・汉弗莱・邓菲
the good reverend Phillip Humphrey Dunphy.
去年一整年  我都在向米奇和小卡暗示
Over the last year, I've dropped a few subtle hints
我也可以当婚礼主持
to Mitch and Cam that I was available.
你们决定让谁做主婚人了吗
Hey, have you guys decided who's gonna officiate your wedding?
我在网上获得牧师资格了
'cause I got ordained online.
天呐  那儿有小袋鼠
Oh, my God. A wallaby!
天呐
Oh, my gosh!
未完待续
To be continued!
菲尔  你真是大救星  谢谢你
Phil, you're a lifesaver. Thank you.
不必感谢
No thanks necessary.
卡梅隆  为你证婚[娶你]
Cameron, marrying you would
让我成了世上最幸福的男人
make me the happiest man on earth.
各位  请注意
Everyone, attention, please!
消防队长刚通知我
I've been informed by the fire chief
我们得马上撤离
we need to leave immediately!
-风向变了  -什么
- The winds have shifted! - What?
但我们有30分钟的啊
But w-we have 30 minutes!
一个婚庆策划同事通知我
A fellow wedding facilitator has informed me
有个美丽的场地刚刚空出来了
a beautiful space just became available.
大家都去摆渡车那里
To the shuttles!
但我们完全不了解那地方的情况
But we don't know a thing about this place.
我的错
Oh, my mistake.
我们快速了解一下
Let's go over it.
那是个古雅充满田园风情的地方
It's a quaint, rustic spot,
但其主要卖点是
though its chief selling point
那里不会变成烧窖
is it's not about to become a kiln!
大家都去摆渡车那里
To the shuttles!
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
翻译：亲爱的小饭  冰蓝  Ethan-泽生  丁小七  罂粟无果
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
家  庭
摩  登
第五季 第二十四集
小卡  把大家从停车场
Cam, where are the shuttles
载到山上的摆渡车都哪儿去了
that brought everyone up from the parking lot?
显然是有别人也订了
Apparently they were double booked.
胡娇已经尽力了
This is the best Pepper could do.
我们就让大家这样去婚礼会场吗
This is how we're getting everyone to the wedding?
我们有一半的来宾是基佬
Half our guests are gay.
他们终于可以有一次
We're finally giving them
不受欺负的校车回忆了
a good memory on a school bus.
那边没有完全缝好
That doesn't look completely sewn on.
你最好找个东西遮一下
You might want to get something to cover that.
好主意
Oh, good idea.
谢谢
Thank you.
你跟莫尔说了什么让他想抛弃巴布
What did you say to Merle that make him want to leave Barb?
我不知道啊
I have no idea!
我们闲聊而已
We were just shooting the breeze --
聊婚礼  迪迪
Wedding day, DeDe,
还有娶了你我有多幸福
how happy I am now that I'm with you.
你为什么要说那些
Why would you say something like that?
你这样可伤透了某人的心
Now you're breaking somebody's heart.
我没想伤害巴布
I didn't mean for her to get hurt.
不是巴布  是莫尔  当他意识到
Not her, him when he realizes
不是每个人的第二任妻子都能有这种身材
that not every second wife looks like this.
谢谢你把外套借给我  杰
Thank you for lending me your jacket, Jay.
知道这世上还有绅士  我很欣慰
It's good to know there are still gentlemen in the world.
是你啊  巴布
Oh, it's you, Barb.
我的美好未来在前方闪耀
I didn't see you there on account of
我都没注意到你
my bright future.
谢谢你  歌洛莉亚
Thank you, Gloria.
勇敢抵抗那个老混蛋[山羊]
Standing up to that old goat
是我做过最棒的事
was best thing I ever did.
那是怎么回事
What's all that about?
不不  是她跟我讲的一个山羊的故事
No, no. The thing is that she told me a story about a goat
山羊很老了  后来这只山羊
and it's very old and then the goat --
别糊弄我
Oh, don't give me that.
我让她勇敢表达自己
I told her to express herself.
我相信一段和谐的婚姻中
I believe that in a good marriage,
女人能够表...
a woman can ex--
好吧  无所谓  我来解决
Fine. Whatever. I'll undo it.
我们不能让小卡知道他父母的情况
We can't let Cam know what the situation with his parents is.
他非常敏感的
He's very delicate.
难以相信  我竟然
I can't believe I'm involved
又一次参与了破坏他人婚姻的事
in breaking up yet another marriage.
什么
What?
你还好吗
Hey, hey. How you holding up?
不是很好
Uh, I've had better days.
但你跟我  我们没事吧
But you and me -- we're cool, right?
有些事情我们可能需要谈一谈
We probably have some things that we should talk about,
但是留在压力没这么大的日子谈吧
but maybe we save it for a less-stressful day.
顺便说一句  这不是你的错
This is not your fault, by the way.
火是不可抗力
the fire was an act of God.
不是说上帝搞了个火球
Not that God sent a fireball down
不让男人和男人结婚  但是...
to keep a couple guys from getting married, but, uh...
我表达得不太好
I didn't say that right.
今天所有的一切都绝不可能
There's no way that this -- any of this --
是上帝的安排
is part of God's plan.
留到敬酒时再说吧  老爸
Save something for the toast, dad.
该死
Damn it.
你想把这个放在哪里
Where do you want this?
五号巴士  你的声音怎么了
Bus five. What's wrong with your voice?
我们三个自驾游去了
The three of us just took a road trip.
去德州边境的路上
We sang Broadway tunes
我们一直在唱百老汇的歌
all the way to the Texas border.
从德州另一面去佛罗里达的路上也是
And then from the other side of Texas to Florida.
所以你是牧师吗
Hey, so you're, like, the minister?
差不多吧  萨尔走后
Kinda. When they lost Sal,
事情变得不费脑筋[没脑子]
the situation was a no-brainer,
所以他们想到了我
which made them think of me.
要证婚不是要记住很多东西吗
Isn't there a lot you have to remember to marry people?
没有啦  都是一样的词儿
Not really. They all follow the same basic pattern.
我们今天齐聚一堂  参加两位新人的
"We're gathered here today to join these two
神圣婚礼
"in holy matrimony.
你愿意让他做你的合法配偶吗
Do you take him to be your lawfully wedded spouse?"
第一个人说
And the first person says --
-我愿意  -对
- I do? - Right.
然后我问第二个人
Then I ask the second person,
你愿意让他做你的合法配偶吗
"Do you take him to be your lawfully wedded spouse?"
-你们知道这一套吧  -对[我愿意]
- You know the drill, right? - I do.
然后我说  根据加利福利亚州
Then I say, "By the powers vested in me
赋予我的权力
by the state of California,
我宣布你们结为合法配偶
I now pronounce you legally wed."
噼里啪啦砰  这婚就结成了
Bingo, bango, bongo, you're married.
太棒了
Awesome.
真的很棒
Really awesome.
巴布  我理解你现在的经历
Look, Barb, I know what you're going through.
你和莫尔的婚姻走到了十字路口
You and Merle are at a crossroads in your marriage.
感觉像是世界末日
It feels like the end of the world,
但是不久后  你会觉得这是...
but in time, you'll see it more as a --
对啊
Right.
就像打嗝一样的小插曲  谁都会经历
A little hiccup that we all go through.
我的建议是  什么都别做
My advice -- don't do anything.
花点时间  喘口气
Just take some time and breathe.
从鼻子里呼气比较好
Maybe through your nose.
你在我的口袋里找到了什么吗
Did you happen to find anything in one of my pockets?
你这样问真奇怪[酒瓶]
Funny you should "Flask."
这个给我吧
Maybe I'll just take that.
不好意思
Excuse me.
现在轻多了  对吧
Well, it's much lighter now, isn't it?
是啊
Yeah.
真奇怪
Okay, this is weird.
我觉得这就是我去学校路上时
I think this is the same seat I used to nervously scratch at
紧张抓挠的座椅
on my way to school.
真可怜
Oh, poor thing.
是啊
Yeah.
我那时就觉得要做到完美好有压力
Even then I felt such pressure to be perfect.
安迪的航班又延误了
Andy's flight is delayed again.
好吧  很接近了
Okay. That was close.
我们差点就在人类水平上有交流了
We almost connected on a human level.
他在做蠢事
He's doing the dumbest thing.
他女朋友和他分手了
His girlfriend broke up with him,
他要飞过去赢回她的心
and he's flying out to win her back.
听起来好浪漫
That sounds so romantic.
太软弱了
It's so weak.
这女生一发脾气  他就跑过去
This girl throws a fit, he goes running.
如果他们复合了  她就大权在握了
If they get back together, she has all the power.
天啊  你喜欢他
Oh, my god. You like him.
不  我才没有  什么啊
No, I don't. What?
太搞笑了
This is so hilarious.
他完全不是你喜欢的类型
He's totally not your type.
闭嘴
Shut up.
拜托  你一直想着他  查看他的情况
Please. You can't stop thinking about him, you're checking on him.
他甚至不像个真人
He's not even like a real person.
他就像个提线木偶
He's like a muppet.
我都不明白萨尔写的一些话
I don't even get some of Sal's remarks here.
婚姻就像是高速公路
"Marriage is like a freeway --
很凌乱  但如果你们交流  就很值得
Messy, but if you communicate, it's so worth it."
亲  那不是"高速公路"[threeway: 三人式]
Honey, that does not say "Freeway."
我不能用这个
I can't use any of this,
但我不想让这场婚礼很普通
but I don't want the whole ceremony to be generic.
应该要有些魔力
There needs to be some magic in it.
你可以读一首诗或者
Well, you can read a poem or maybe --
等等  往回倒
Hold on. Back up.
我喜欢你的上一个主意  变魔术
I like your last idea -- a magic trick.
我没有提议要变魔术
I did not suggest a magic trick.
毕竟  有什么比魔术
After all, what's better than magic
更能象征婚姻的美好呢
to symbolize the wonder of marriage?!
抱歉  我在和你说话呢
Excuse me. I'm talking to you.
好吧
Yeah, yeah.
在商店里你穿起来还不错
They looked good on you in the store,
但现在你不确定了
but now you're not sure.
那是十分钟前的话题
That was the topic 10 minutes ago.
也许我把体育版贴到我头上
Well, maybe if I stapled the sports page to my head,
你就会注意到我了
you'd pay attention.
只要能盖住你的嘴
As long as it covered your mouth.
-什么  -没事
- What? - Nothing.
我们什么时候才能到啊
Ugh, when are we going to be there?
快了  亲爱的  很快了
Soon, honey. Very soon.
来  笑一个
Come on. Give us a smile.
记住  这是你爸爸们生命中
Remember, this is the happiest day
最快乐的一天
of your dads' lives.
蝴蝶在吃我
The butterflies are eating me!
谁要你碰那个盒子的
Well, who told you to jostle the crate?!
一只飞进了我嘴里
Oh, blah. One got in my mouth.
真是一群小孩
What a bunch of babies.
胡娇说这里很棒  希望我们会喜欢
Pepper said it was nice. I hope we like it.
小卡  不管帘子那边是什么样
Cam, Cam, listen, whatever's on the other side of this curtain,
我们都不能失望
we cannot be disappointed.
你说得对
You're right.
今天的重点不是花朵或其他肤浅的事
Today is not about flowers or superficial things.
对  好吧
Right. Okay.
-谢天谢地  -好漂亮  我害怕死了
- Oh, thank god. - It's pretty. I was so scared!
我超喜欢  我都要哭了
Oh, I love it, I love it. I could cry!
别哭了  会把脸上打的修容粉毁掉的
Oh, don't cry. You'll streak your bronzer.
大家请就坐
Everyone, please take your seats!
我们五分钟[西语]后开始
We'll be starting in cinco minutes,
也就是最多十分钟
10 at the most.
你有没有发现罗纳多的
Do you ever notice with Ronaldo
语言障碍时不时会发作是吗
how his language barrier sort of fluctuates?
这地方是怎么订到的
How is this place even available?
可怕的故事
Oh, dreadful story.
新娘跑了  新郎闹自杀  世仇家族
Runaway bride, suicidal groom, feuding families.
相比之下我们的小问题真是不值一提
It really puts our mundane problems in perspective.
灯光不能调暗
Oh, we can't dim the lights.
那就打碎几盏
Then break some.
他们已没有年轻人那么无敌的皮肤了
These are not young men!
你们去梳洗打扮一下吧
Why don't you two go freshen up?
等等
Wait.
为什么四重奏只来了一半
Why am I seeing only half a quartet?
埃德和吉姆是志愿消防员
Ed and jim are volunteer firemen.
可不是嘛
Of course they are.
你们尽量找面镜子对着弹吧
Try to play in front of a mirror.
-幸运之吻  - 好吧  好吧
- A kiss for luck. - Oh, okay. Yes.
给我个幸运吻  我的小姜饼
A kiss for luck, my little gingersnap!
好吧  巴布
Oh, okay. Oh, wow, barb.
幸好我们已经出了火灾区
Oh, oh, good thing we're out of the fire zone.
要知道你爸爸给了我个婚礼小帮手
Well, you know your dad gave me a little wedding helper.
我不知道我外套里面还有一个
I didn't know the jacket still had a --
酒瓶  是啊  真好
Flask. Yeah. Oh, that's nice.
你知道  在仪式结束时
You know, at the end of the ceremony,
我要亲一个男人
I kiss a man,
所以你把酒瓶装满做好准备吧
so you might want to fill 'er up.
你就这么解决问题吗
This is how you try to fix things?
-把她灌醉  -别怪他
- You get her drunk? - Don't blame him.
自从她去了那个
She's been a loose cannon
十点半开始祈祷仪式的教堂
ever since she started going
她就变成了一个定时炸弹
to that church service that starts at 10:30.
他们还弹吉他呢
They play guitar music.
那是个庆祝活动
It's a celebration.
那是个罪恶之城
It's gomorrah.
牧师还戴着麦当娜唱歌用的麦克风呢
The pastor wears one of them madonna microphones.
什么麦当娜唱歌用的麦克风
Oh, madonna microphones.
我的小玉米须哪里去了
Where's my little corn silk?
这事结束之后你想去做点儿有意思的事吗
Hey, you want to go out and do something fun after this thing?
不  我想今晚在家呆着
No, I was thinking about staying in tonight
好好陪陪乔
and spending some time with joe.
自从有了那孩子
Ugh, you never want to do anything
你就什么都不想做了
since that baby came along.
-你怎么样  -我很好
- How are you? - I'm good.
你带了  那个
You -- you have the, um --
结婚证  戒指  签字笔  祝酒词吗
Marriage license, rings, signing pen, toast?
是的  当然都带了
Yes, of course.
不然怎么会叫我伴人[最棒的人]呢
There's a reason I'm the best person.
这只是在今天才有的称呼而已
You know that's just a title for today, right?
是的  我是这个婚礼上最棒的人
Yeah, I'm the best person at this wedding.
我还是会听到...  那是什么
I'm still kind of hearing -- what is that?
我的天  我的上帝
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
慢着
Wait. Oh.
沾上花粉了  不是吧
That's pollen. Oh, no.
-亲爱的  -别看我
- Honey. - Don't look at me.
我只有那一个胸花
I only had one corsage.
你姐姐哪去了
Where's your sister?
海莉
Haley?
安迪  你还在这里呢
Andy! You're still here?
是啊
Yeah.
因为天气原因我的航班一直被推迟
My flight keeps getting delayed because of weather.
我们的婚礼也是
Oh, so does the wedding.
等等  火灾算天气原因吗
Wait. Is fire weather?
-着火了吗  -是的
- There was a fire? - Yeah.
怪不得你的裙子热辣得冒烟
Guess that explains that smoking dress.
注意分寸  安迪
Line, Andy.
那个  如果你想打发时间
Well, if you're -- if you're just killing time,
新的婚宴场地就在附近
the new wedding venue is nearby.
你完全可以过来转转
You could totally come and hang.
我觉得我的穿着不太合适
I don't think I'm exactly dressed for it.
当然如果我跟你在一起
Of course, if I was with you,
没有人会去看我的
no one would even look at me.
好了
Wow, okay.
你馅饼吃得够多了  年轻人
That is quite enough pie for you, young man.
我得回去了
Ugh. I've got to get back.
那个  我来这里不是为了喝咖啡的
Um, look, I didn't come here for coffee.
安迪  我觉得你不应该
Andy, I don't think it's a good idea
上这班飞机
for you to get on that plane.
我不觉得贝丝值得你这样付出
I don't think Beth is worth it.
你根本不了解贝丝
You don't even know Beth.
我想我了解
I think I do.
我想我之前和她一样
I think I've been her.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你写十封信她只回一封
For every 10 letters you write, she writes one.
她永远是先挂断电话的那个人
She's always the one who ends the phone call.
你不经意间提起你自己的生日
You happen to mention when your birthday's coming up
因为你心里知道她早已经忘了
because you know deep down she's already forgotten it.
与此同时  她给你的刚好够拴住你的心
Meanwhile, she gives you just enough to keep you on the hook.
喂
Hello?
我当然没走  妈妈
Of course I didn't leave, mom.
几秒钟前你才从我身边路过
You walked past me two seconds ago.
我想说的是  你值得拥有更好的
I'm just saying, you deserve better.
我的天啊
Oh, my god!
我正跟你招手呢
I'm waving at you!
站着别动
Stay where you are!
我正在朝你走
I'm walking towards you!
莉莉  来  我需要你的胸花
Lily, here you go. I'm taking your corsage.
可那是我的
But it's mine.
你是花童
You're the flower girl.
给别人花是你的工作
It's part of your job.
好好读读你的合同  谢谢
Read the fine print. Thank you.
-克莱尔  -怎么了
- Claire! - What?
我需要戒指
I-I need the rings.
-干什么  -排练我们的魔术
- For what? - To practice our trick.
拜托拜托  快来
Come on, come on, come on.
亲爱的  我不确定该不该变魔术
Oh, honey, I don't know about the magic trick.
你不觉得大家应该把注意力
Don't you think people should be
集中在小卡和米奇身上吗
focused on Cam and Mitch?
我正希望是  他们是完美的掩饰
I'm hoping so. It's the perfect misdirect.
好了  我们来这么做
Okay, here's how we're gonna do this.
-你拿着戒指  -好吧
- You hold the rings. - Okay.
我说  "人们说最好的婚姻
I say, "They say the best marriages
拥有一点点魔力"
contain just a little bit of magic."
我们举起手臂
We hold up our arms.
你放开戒指
You let go of the rings.
戒指顺着线滑下来
They slide down the thread
仿佛神奇地飘过来一样
as if mysteriously floating
一路滑到  中间位置
all the way -- half the way to me.
莫尔  我知道你和杰谈过之后
Merle, I know that after talking to Jay,
你觉得你能找到更好的
you think that there are better things out there for you.
谁说不会呢
Who says there isn't?
好吧
Okay.
我们来看看未来是什么样子
Take a trip with me to the future.
当地廉价酒吧里的一个普通夜晚
It's a regular night at the local honky tonk.
看哪  是谁独自一人坐在吧台
Look, who's that man sitting alone in the bar?
是莫尔
It's Merle.
一个美女款款走来
A beautiful woman approaches.
她问  "你旁边有人坐吗"
She asks, "Is this seat taken?"
他说"没有"  然后她拿过椅子
He says, "No," and then she grabs the chair
走去坐在一个更年轻
and goes sits next to a much younger,
更帅气的男人身边
much handsomer-looking man.
莫尔转头对酒保说
Then Merle turns around to the bartender
"星期二快乐  是吧"
And say, "Happy Tuesday, huh?"
酒保回答说
The bartender replies,
你想说的是"圣诞快乐"吧
"Don't you mean 'Merry Christmas'?"
看到了吧  莫尔
You see, Merle?
你圣诞节孤零零一人在喝酒
It was Christmas the whole time!
可以开始了  乐队奏乐
Okay, it's show time. Cue the processional.
菲尔  用我老家南卡罗来那州的话说
Phil, as they say in my native South Carolina,
该给你弟的男人证婚了[娶他]
it's time to marry your brother-in-law.
小花童  撒花瓣吧
Flower girl, work those petals.
新人入场
Wedding party walking.
什么事
What's that?
我马上过去
I'll be right there.
好了  最后检查一下
Okay. Last looks.
你超帅的
Very handsome.
这是你的正装里我第二喜欢的
This is my second favorite suit of yours.
第二喜欢
Second?
我最喜欢你生日穿的那套
Right after your birthday suit.
别说了  人家都是已婚男人了
Hey. Cut it out. I'm practically a married man.
我知道
I know.
我刚刚被你爸说的话吓到了
You know, you scared me earlier with what your dad said.
怎么了
W-what?
就是关于山火
Well, just about the fire, you know...
预示着我们不该结婚的事
being a sign we shouldn't get married.
有点末日预言的感觉
It was kind of apocalypticy.
-才不是呢  -然后天就黑了
- No. - Then the sky turned dark.
没错  因为有山火
Yeah, because of the fire.
然后发了"洪水"
Well, and then we had a flood.
你懂的  萨尔的羊水破了
You know, Sal -- sploosh.
我觉得你脑洞开得有点大
I think you're stretching just a little bit.
因为我们花钱订了房间
Because we paid for this room!
卢卡斯夫妇  我们只要20分钟
Mr. and Mrs. Lucas, we just need 20 minutes!
把音乐停下
Cut the boy soprano.
不行  让这些人都出去
No, we need these people out of here!
你还是想逃婚对不对
I can see you want to run again, don't you?
追随你的心
Follow your heart.
各就各位  预备  过自己的生活去吧
On your mark, get set, live, baby!
你不需要这个
You don't need that!
你不觉得这又是一个上帝的旨意吗
You don't see this as another biblical sign?
乔治・卢卡斯: 其公司出品的一款星战游戏
不允许同性角色之间产生恋情
一大群卢卡斯们
A swarm of "Lucases."
各位  安排有点小变动
Slight change, everyone!
不用担心
Don't worry!
我们有第三套备用方案
There's always a plan "C"!
天呐  到处都是蝴蝶
Oh! They're everywhere!
你们都是什么毛病啊
What is wrong with you people?
别去动盒子了
Leave the box alone!
要是把那个拿进来
Oh, if that thing is coming in,
更多宾客就得站到草坪上去了
we need to put a few more people on the lawn.
这个地方还算舒适吧
Okay, this place is cozy, right?
没错  没错  没错
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
这里很好  一切都会好的
It's fine. It's -- oh, it's going to be fine.
就是  就是  就是
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
不过我们可能需要
Although we may need to
让一部分宾客坐到楼上
sit some of the overflow guests upstairs.
楼上不是我们的
Oh, we don't -- we don't own the upstairs.
是吗
Really?
我一直以为你家还有更好的地方
I always assumed there was a nicer part
没让我看过
you weren't showing me.
确保他们把账单都付清
Make sure their checks have cleared.
再找一个餐饮服务商来
Just get another caterer here
不然这些人就只能喝蝴蝶汤了
or these people will be eating butterfly bisque!
我在尝试冷静下来
Okay, I'm trying to remain calm,
可是你不觉得这又是一个凶兆吗
but you realize that's another sign of the apocalypse, right?
饥荒吗
Famine?
他听起来跟斯蒂芬和斯特凡
He sounds as bad as Steven, Stefan,
和朗吉娜一样糟
and Longines.
末世论中天启四骑士分别代表瘟疫  战争  饥荒和死亡
你是想说我们有四个
Oh, so what you're saying
嘶哑的男人[骑士]吗
is we have four hoarse men?
别皱着眉头了
Stop with the frowning.
今天要为你们的儿子保持笑容
Today, you smile for your son.
明天你们想做什么都可以
Tomorrow, you can do whatever you want.
明天我大概就搬出去了
Tomorrow, I might just move out.
现在我感觉到笑意了
Oh, now I feel a smile coming on.
天啊  你在给安迪发短信吗
Oh, my god. You're texting Andy now?
我只是告诉他愿意的话可以来玩
I'm just letting him know he can hang out here if he wants.
海莉  我希望你知道自己在干什么
Haley, I hope you know what you're doing.
我什么也没做
I'm not doing anything.
你要是真的喜欢他是一回事
I mean, it's one thing if you're actually into him,
可如果你只是想
but if you're just playing around with him
跟他玩玩
for the fun of it...
对于安迪这种单纯善良的人来说
Here's the thing about nice, quiet dorks like Andy.
我们需要花比你多得多的时间
You get over us much faster than
放下一段感情
we get over you.
不好意思  真对不起
Hi. Sorry. So sorry.
不好意思  里面是我老公
Excuse me. It's my husband.
人们说最好的婚姻
"They say the best marriages" --
我不是要催你
I don't mean to rush you,
可是外面已经排了有80多个人了
but there's like 80 people waiting to get in here.
不不不  你来了正好
No, no, no. I'm so glad you're here.
我刚想到了一个新的魔术
I just worked up a new magic trick.
我先说  "人们说最好的婚姻
I start by saying, "They say the best marriages
需要一点点魔力"
contain just a little bit of magic."
而袖子里装着我从莉莉柜子里找到的
Then in my sleeves, I've rigged two confetti poppers
两管彩色纸屑
that I found in Lily's closet.
到时我一抬手
So when I raise my arms...
真的吗  你怎么不说"别这么做"
Really? You're not gonna say, "Don't do that"?
不  我不觉得这是个好主意
No, I mean, I don't think you need the magic trick,
可是如果你要做  效果一定会很好
but if you do it, I'm sure you'll be great.
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
天啊  别动我来  亲爱的  不
Oh, god, let me get that. Honey! No!
亲爱的  不  小心
Honey, no! Hey!
菲尔  不
Phil! Oh, no!
不要  水开了  水开了
No, no, water's on! Water's on!
不  你
No! You --
-请稍等  -请稍等
-Just a minute. - Just a minute.
-你好  安迪  -你好
-Hey Andy. - Hey.
婚礼开始了吗
Has the wedding started yet?
开始好几次了
Oh, yeah, lots of times.
-怎么了  -没什么
-What's up? - Oh, nothing.
你之前说的关于我值得更好的人
Hey, that thing you said before about me deserving better,
你就那么一说  对吧
you just meant, like, in general, right?
你不是在说某个特定的人对吧
You weren't thinking of anyone in particular?
对  不  我的意思是你值得拥有幸福
Yeah, no, I-I just meant you deserve to be happy.
如果这个女孩能让你幸福  再好不过
And if it's this girl, great.
如果不是她  那也很好
If not, great.
有些时候  最难的事
Um, sometimes the hardest part
是弄清楚自己想要什么
is just figuring out what you want.
我也是这么想的
Yeah, that's what I thought.
玩得开心
Well, enjoy the wedding.
谢谢  一路平安
Thanks. Have a nice trip.
再见
Yeah. I'll see you.
新婚
真高兴我们做到了
I'm so glad we did this.
那当然  我们这么认真
I know. Who were we kidding?
必须能做到
It was so gonna happen.
实在太搞笑了
I can't get enough of this.
不  米奇没事  不过还在生我的气
No, Mitch is fine. Still mad at me, though.
你也知道他有时是多么敏感易怒  迪迪
You know how touchy he can be, Dede.
你还记得在他第一次参加完滑冰比赛后
Remember when we tried to cheer him up
我们试图哄他开心的事吗
after his first ice-skating competition?
我们怎么知道第三名是好事啊
How were we supposed to know third place is a good thing?
还记得他穿着旱冰鞋
Remember he tromped off
在泥地里乱踩的场景吗
across that muddy field in his skates?
他像个猛犸象一样陷了下去
He sunk like a woolly mammoth.
对了迪迪  如果你国庆节时有空的话
Hey, Dede, if you're around the fourth of July,
就过来观看一下婚礼录像吧
you should come by and watch the wedding video.
不  我们八月会出城
No, we're out of town in August.
好吧  很快的  好的
All right. Well, soon. Okay.
迪迪  我好像没有你的新...
Oh, Dede, I don't think I have your new --
好了  见证奇迹的时刻到了
Okay, it's magic time, everyone!
菲尔  请在庄严的拱门下就位
Phil, please take your place beneath our majestic arch.
开始演奏吧
Cue the quartet.
还有一个人去哪儿了
Where's the other one?
他跟那个把货车开翻了的餐饮承办员跑了
He rode with the caterer who flipped his truck.
为什么大家都摊上了好事  就我没有呢
Why do good things happen to everyone but me?
赶快派上花童吧
Let's send the flower girl
再等她就长成花季少女了
before she's a flower teenager.
好悲伤
Oh, so sad.
抱歉
Sorry.
-搞毛  -行了  搞得像问题出在我身上一样
- What is ... - Yeah. Like I'm the problem.
你爸在这儿吗
Is your dad here?
是的  他应该很快就...
Yeah, he should be right --
天啊
Oh -- oh, my god.
他在外面人行道上打电话呢
He's out on the sidewalk on the phone.
你需要我去叫他吗
Do you want me to go get him?
不  不想  我们就...算了
No, no, I don't. Let's just -- come on.
我们直接开始吧
Let's just do this.
米奇尔
Mitchell.
你真的想就这样完成婚礼吗
Is this really how you want to get married?
是不理想
Well, it's not ideal.
不行  人们都没有米可抛洒
No, people don't have any rice to throw
因为他们都饿得吃生米了
because they're chewing it raw out of starvation.
一半的宾客在外面的草坪上
Half of our guests are on the lawn and...
洒水车来了
There go the sprinklers.
好吧  我们宣布"婚礼死亡"算了吧
Okay, let's just call time of death on this.
好吧
All right, yeah.
那个  大家  非常感谢你们
Hey, everybody, um, thank you so much
今天承受这么多的折腾
for, uh, for dealing with all this today.
那对我们意义重大
It means a lot to us.
但不幸的是  这场婚礼实在...
But unfortunately, this is not gon--
停  你不能这么做
Stop. You can't do this.
我已经赶在你前面停止了
I'm way ahead of you, dad,
谢谢你能赏光过来
and thank you for stopping by.
我的意思是  你不能像这样草草就结婚
What I mean is, you can't get married like this.
你们两个值得拥有一场
You two deserve the kind of wedding
你们在过去的9个月中
you've been talking about nonstop
不停挂在嘴边的梦幻婚礼
for the last nine months.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
你们一有机会就会谈论婚礼
You bring it up every chance that you get.
我知道"不停"二字是什么意思
I know what nonstop means!
相信我  好吗
Trust me, okay?
我们都站在这儿干嘛啊
Now, what are we all standing around for?
我儿子今天要结婚了
My son's getting married today.
恭喜  杰
All right, Jay.
那正是这所高尔夫俱乐部需要的
It's what this golf club needs.
改变一下旧风貌
Shake it up a little.
上吧  小宝贝
Go on, dear.
爸爸们能结几次婚啊
How often do your fathers get married?
目前已经结了一次  两次
So far, one, two...
你赶紧给我滚出吧
Why am I still seeing you?
你可以坐下了  老爸
You can take your seat, dad.
我们要开始了
We're about to start.
我觉得我们父子俩要小走一段
Actually, I thought you and I would take a little walk.
我感觉一切仿如昨日
I remember it like it was yesterday --
米奇尔被从医院抱回的那天
The day that Mitchell came home from the hospital
身上裹着土的掉渣的白色尿布
in a very unfashionable white diaper
头上是三缕杂乱分布的头发
with three strands of scraggly raggedy andy hair.
如果他要牵儿子走红毯  那我也要
If he's doing it, I'm doing it.
你一起来吗  巴布
You coming, Barb?
你可真是老甜心
You old sweet talker.
等等我
Wait for me!
我们从此变得不可分离
We were inseparable.
我是他的大姐
I was his big sister,
也是他的大哥  他的死对头
his big brother, his nemesis,
他的保护人  也是他最亲密的朋友
his protector, his best friend.
我的他的第一个搭档
I was his first partner.
我享受当中的每一分每一秒
And I loved every minute of it.
感谢大家参与这一盛大的喜事
Thank you all for being here on this happy occasion.
人们常说最好的婚姻都蕴含着一丝魔力
They say the best marriages contain just a little bit of magic.
相信我
Believe me.
我深有感触
I know.
我们相聚在此  参加一对璧人的婚礼
We're gathered here today to join two amazing people.
自然  在由谁来取代我这件事上
So naturally, I was a little picky
我会表现得有一点吹毛求疵
when it came to who was going to be replacing me,
然后我认识了这个叫小卡的人
And then I met this Cam.
当然  他很温暖  风趣  有爱
And sure, he was warm and funny and loving.
卡梅隆  你愿意让米奇尔成为你的丈夫吗
Cameron, do you take Mitchell to be your husband?
我愿意
I do.
卡梅隆  请你为米奇尔戴上戒指
Cameron, would you please place this ring on Mitchell's finger?
米奇尔  你愿意让卡梅隆成为你的丈夫吗
Mitchell, do you take Cameron to be your husband?
我愿意
I do.
那么凭借加州政府授予我的权力
Then by the powers vested in me by the state of California,
我宣布你们结为终身配偶
I am privileged to pronounce you spouses for life.
你们可以行"夫夫吻"了
You may now kiss your husband.
我也曾疑惑
I wondered,
"他真的是我期望
"Was he really
与我弟弟幸福相伴的那个人吗
everything I wanted for my brother?
他真的是最棒的那个人吗"
Was he really the best person?"
不  我才是"伴人"
No, I'm the best person.
现在我想举起杯子
And now I am very pleased to raise a glass
第一次隆重地向大家介绍
And introduce for the first time ever --
尽管这已经是第4次尝试了
on our fourth try --
天造地设的一对夫夫  米奇和小卡
great husbands, Mitch and Cam.
恭喜
Yes!
我看到了
I saw that.
什么啊
What?
你看我老姐的眼神
The way you look at my sister.
你老是这么色眯眯的
You do it all the time, you know.
我才没有呢
I do not.
别当着我的面这样  好吗
Just not in front of me, okay?
你两位老爸去度蜜月了  有跟你联系吗
So, have you heard from your dads on their honeymoon?
你一定很想他们吧
You must really miss them, don't you?
抱歉  我有点小题大做了
Sorry. I was being dramatic.
怎么会  你说得很对
No, you were right.
你会自厌自弃的
You'll hate yourself.
又来了
Right again.
就像他们根本没离开一样
It's like they never left.